

### **Personal Info**

Date of birth14/3 1995NationalityEgyptianMarital StatusExemptedPhone(+20) 1119421377

E-mail

moh.shehata143@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

<u>linkedin.com/in/muhammad-shehata-450116145</u>

#### **Github**

https://github.com/MohamedSheha taAbdalla?tab=repositories

### **Skills**

PHP OOP & Laravel

My SQL & SQL Server

Mongodb & HTTP & REST API

HTML & CSS & Sass

Bootstrap & JS & React.js

Basic UI UX Design

DB Schema & Git

### **Additional Skills**

C#, APS.net, Vue.js, jQuery, WordPress Plugin's, Neo4j DevExpress, Crystal Reports

### Soft Skills

**Problem Solving** 

Collaboration

Flexibility

## Languages

Arabic Native Language
English good knowledge

I'm a Web Developer and Computer Science Researcher. I've more than 3 years of experience building web and desktop applications using ASP.NET and PHP. I've worked internationally remotely and also worked internally on projects for businesses, agencies, and start-ups.

### **Experience**

### Jan-2021 -Present

## **Full Stack Web Developer**

Business Expert Services, Orlando Florida, USA.

- Worked on analyzing many projects, UI design, and database schema.
- Designed and Developed 3 web Site using Laravel, Mongodb, Bootstrap.
- Create and Customize for 2 WordPress Plugins using PHP.

# Oct-2018 - Present

## Teaching Assistant of MIS

Higher Institute for Advanced Studies in Haram, Giza, Egypt.

- Training students on the practical and relevant contents of the Material.
- Training students to implement projects for all practical materials, and receive projects from students and discuss.
- Evaluating students, controlling the work of the year.

# May-2018 - Oct-2019

## Web Developer

S-Smart, Giza, Egypt.

- Worked on analyzing many projects and determining customer requirements.
- worked on more than 10 SQL database design projects and Improved speed to complete projects.
- Designed, Developed, and provided maintenance for 10+ webs applications and desktop applications using C#, SQL Server. Achieved 100% client satisfaction.

## May-2017 -May-2018

# Freelance Front-End Web Developer

- Communicated with customers to implement Web Services.
- Trouble-shot and fixed problems through customer requests.
- Designed and Developed for 15+ websites using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, JS, jQuery.

### **Certificates**

- **2021** Mobile Application Development Certification, Egyptian Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
- **2016** International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL) certification, Microsoft.
- **2014** Personal Strategic Planning Certification, IAPTLD Professional Trainer (PT).

# **Education**

Oct 2021 - Expected 2022	Pre-Masters in Computer Science in Progress Faculty of Graduate Studies and Statistical Research, Cairo University, Egypt.
Oct 2019 - May 2021	<b>Diploma in Computer Science</b> Faculty of Graduate Studies and Statistical Research, Cairo University, Egypt. 3.13 GPA
May 2014 - May 2018	<ul> <li>Bachelor of Management Information Systems</li> <li>Higher Institute of Advanced Studies in Haram, Egypt.</li> <li>3.54 GPA</li> <li>I Participated in the science club's competition for innovations and inventions (Workshops), 2018.</li> <li>I received a certificate for the Science Club's Competition, 2018.</li> </ul>

## Courses

Nov - Des 2020	Diploma in Mobile Application Development (Flutter) Online by The Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
Oct 2020	Diploma in Life Skills Online by The Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
July 2014 - Sept 2016	ICDL v5 Professional Training for ICDL Curriculum Software Development Center and Medical Engineering Consultancy. Cairo University.
Apr - Aug 2014	Diploma in Human Development Smart Center in Bani Mazar. Minya.
July - Aug 2010	Professional Training for Microsoft Office 2003 Office Application Packs Secondary School for Boys New Beni Mazar. Minya.